>> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 好的，让我们深入到词法范围，
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: All right, so
let's dig into lexical scope,
我们来看看这个特殊的代码
let's take a look at this particular code.
这应该很眼熟
This should look familiar,
这是我们以前所做的一样的代码
this is the same kind of code
that we were doing before.
在作者的时候
And at author time,
当我决定让函数在函数 otherClass() 中提问时。
when I decided to put the function ask
inside of the function otherClass().
我无可挽回地决定了变量的参考
I irrevocably decided that
the variable reference
第 7 行将指向第 4 行中声明的变量。
on line 7 is going to point at
the variable that was declared on line 4.
换句话说，大理石颜色是在编译时决定的。
In other words the marble color
was decided at compile time.
其实不是这个样子
It's not actually this look up process,
就像我们在运行时讨论的那样
like we discussed during
the run time phase.
当我用叙述式给你一个概念模型时，我就把它用在了一个纤维床上。
I sort of fibbed when I used that in the
narrative to give you a conceptual model.
但在运行时，不是要说哎，范围，问，
But it is not the case that at run
time it has to say hey, scope of ask,
你听说过这个大理石吗
have you ever heard of this marble?
还有其他课的范围你听说过这个大理石吗
And hey, scope of other class,
have you ever heard of this marble?
因为至少这个节目的写方式
Because at least the way
this program's written,
我们知道大理石是什么颜色
we know at compile time
what color the marble is.
甚至在最坏的情形下
And even in the worst case scenario,
where we might for
有些理由不知道这个颜色的大理石是什么时候的，
some reason not know what the color
marble was from the compile time.
我们会第一次把它弄明白
We're gonna figure it out
the very first time, and
那么我们就不需要再想办法了，我们永远不会改变的
then we don’t need to figure it out
ever again, cuz it’s never gonna change.
所以词法作用的原因之一是
So one of the reasons why
lexical scope is actually so
流行的原因是它是如此的乐观主义。
popular is because it’s so optimizable.
这个想法是你在整理东西的时候可以决定的
This idea that you can decide
when you're compiling things,
所有这些变量都来自
where all of those variables come from,
这些弹珠的颜色是什么，我们不需要在运行时发现这些东西。
what color the marbles are, we don’t need
to figure that stuff out at runtime.
这就是你从词法范围中得到的东西。
That’s what you should
get from lexical scope.
能帮我保住我脑袋里的界限的方法之一
One of the ways that helps me
keep those boundaries in my head.
这也是我喜欢写函数表达式的原因之一
And it's also one of the reasons why I
like writing out function expressions in
他们的完整形式
their full form and
嵌套而不是尝试在一行上一起字符串。
nested rather than trying to string
everything together on one line.
我喜欢看函数界和我喜欢的过程
Is I like to see the function boundaries
and I like to mentally process
在每一个范围内都有一个气泡
that there's essentially a bubble
around each of these scopes.
周围有个泡沫，还有一个其他阶级的泡沫，然后一个泡沫
There's a bubble around ask, and a bubble
around other class, and then a bubble
在全球范围内，这些气泡被严格地嵌套在彼此之间。
around the global scope, and these bubbles
are strictly nested inside of each other.
这样他们就不喜欢穿过线了
So it's not like they're
gonna cross the line.
我们不可能有一个范围在两个父母的范围内
It's not like we're gonna have one scope
that's partially in two parent scopes,
它们完全包含在彼此之间
they're entirely contained
within each other.
事实上，在气泡的内部视觉化这些范围，
As a matter of fact, visualizing
these scopes inside of the bubbles,
而这也是我最喜欢的想法
while it's kind of my preferred
way of thinking about it.
还有一种视觉视觉化的方法让它足够有效
There's another way of visualizing
this that is effective enough that it
可以在你的编辑里出现
can actually show up
inside of your editor.
在我的编辑中，我使用的是崇高的，我想我之前已经说过了。
In my editor I use sublime,
I think I've mentioned before.
在我的编辑器中，我有一个插件，可以在方式上切换。
In my editor, I have a plugin
that I can switch on a mode.
它使用一个叫做 ES 级别的工具，它是一个分析
It uses a tool called ES levels,
which is a tool that analyzes
你的水桶和弹珠的作用范围
the scope levels of where basically
all your buckets and marbles are.
这就是当我用同一条代码的时候
And this is what it looks like when
I take that same piece of code and
我把它放在我的编辑器里
I turn it on inside of my editor.
您会注意到它正在对不同的变量引用进行着色，并且
You'll notice that it is coloring
the different variable references and
根据它们所属的范围来执行不同的代码段。
the different pieces of code according
to what scope they belong to.
它基本上是给你你的斗彩颜色和大理石颜色。
It's basically giving you your bucket
colors and your marble colors.
你会注意到第 7 行有一个颜色被引用
And you'll notice down on line 7 that
there's a color being referenced for
与第 4 行的老师匹配。
teacher and
that matches the one from line 4.
>> [INAUDIBLE] >> 凯尔 - 辛普森:
&gt;&gt; [INAUDIBLE]
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: So again,
这是一个叫做 ES 级别的插件。
this is a plugin that's called ES levels.
现在，这并不完美，它确实有一些问题。
Now, it is not perfect,
it does have some quirks to it.
如果您注意到此特定示例，其中 I 具有名称函数表达式，
If you notice this particular example,
where I have a name function expression,
记得我们谈过函数表达式的名称吗 ?
remember what we talked about with
the names of function expressions?
这些名字应该在其外层范围内。
Those names are supposed to go
inside of their enclosing scope.
那么为什么第 1 行的 foo 就像在外部范围内那样 ?
So why is that foo on line 1 colored
as if it is in the outer scope?
如果它是函数声明，但在这里他们会为
It would if it was a function declaration,
but here they're doing that for
函数表达式。
a function expression.
多年前我向 ES 级的项目报告了这个
Years ago I reported this
to the ES level's project,
并且说这是一个应该有颜色的缺陷，就像它属于这个范围。
and said this is a bug that should be
colored as if it belongs to the scope.
他们做了一整一簇的工作
And they did a whole bunch of well,
actuallys on,
从技术上来说名字就在它的中间范围内
technically that name is in
its own intermediate scope.
因此，赋予它同样的颜色也是对的。
And so it would even be right
to give it the same colors, and
然后他们就做了这么久的事
then they went on this big long thing.
他们会说如果我们真的这么做的话我们会有太多的颜色
And they'd say we'd have too many
colors if we did it the real way, so
我们只会让它单独离开我们会让它崩溃的
we're just gonna leave it alone,
we're just gonna leave it broken.
所以它不是完美的，但有时会有很大的帮助，可以看到
So it's not perfect, but it is super
helpful at times to be able to see where
这些变量是来自这些变量，还是为什么我被这些变量混淆了 ?
are these variables coming from, or why am
I getting so confused by these variables?
那我就翻那个插件了
So I'll flip that plugin in.
但我喜欢视觉化我的范围界限的想法。
But I like the idea of
visualizing my scope boundaries.
它能帮助我保持所有的词法范围
It helps me keep all of
the lexical scopes straight.